<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <body>
    <section name="About Opal Toolkit">
      <p>
 The Grid-based infrastructure enables large-scale scientific applications
 to be run on distributed resources and coupled in innovative ways. However,
 in practice, Grid resources are not very easy to use for the end-users who
 have to learn how to generate security credentials, stage inputs and
 outputs, access Grid-based schedulers, and install complex client software.
 There is an imminent need to provide transparent access to these resources
 so that the end-users are shielded from the complicated details, and free
 to concentrate on their domain science. Scientific applications wrapped as
 Web services alleviate some of these problems by hiding the complexities of
 the back-end security and computational infrastructure, only exposing a
 simple SOAP API that can be accessed programmatically by
 application-specific user interfaces. However, writing the application
 services that access Grid resources can be quite complicated, especially if
 it has to be replicated for every application. Towards that end, we have
 implemented Opal, which is a toolkit for wrapping scientific applications
 as Web services in a matter of hours, providing features such as
 scheduling, standards-based Grid security and data management in an
 easy-to-use and configurable manner.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="News">

        <iframe src="rss2html.php?XMLFILE=http://sourceforge.net/export/rss2_projnews.php?group_id=211778"
                 width="100%" frameborder="0" height="400" > 
	</iframe>
    </section>

    <section name="Why Opal?">

      <p>The salient features of Opal are as follows:
      <ul>
	<li>Opal enables deployment of scientific applications as Web
        services without having to write a single line of Web services code</li>
        <li>Opal exposes the scientific functionality through a generic Web
        services API (via a standard WSDL)</li>
        <li>Opal hides the complexity involved in the submission of
        computational jobs to Grid resources</li>
        <li>Opal manages user data, which includes creation of working
        directories, input and output data staging, and persistent storage
        for job information and metadata</li>
	<li>Opal services can be configured with GSI-based security for
        authentication and authorization purposes</li>
	<li>Opal services can be accessed from a multitude of languages
        (Java, Python, Perl, JavaScript) and plaforms (Windows, various
        Unix flavors)</li>
      </ul>
      </p>

      <p>So why use Opal, and not just Globus GRAM to launch remote jobs? Here are some reasons.
      <ul>
      <li>Deploying an application as an Opal service is very easy, and can be
      achieved under a couple of hours. It can often be done much faster
      than that, once the first Opal service has already been deployed.
      After the necessary software has been downloaded and installed,
      adding a new service is a matter of modifying a few configuration
      files and using an Ant script to deploy the service.</li>
      <li>Every user doesn't have to deploy the application. From our
      experience, we have learnt that deploying a scientific application can
      be quite complicated if it has to be done by every user. If Opal is
      used, the service provider deploys this application once which can then
      be used by any client via a SOAP API.</li>
      <li>Every user would typically need an account on the cluster if they use
      the traditional Globus GRAM approach. In theory, multiple client DN's
      could be mapped to a generic group user account - but this means that
      all the users have to ensure that they don't interfere with others
      who may be logged on to the same account. The Opal approach is much
      cleaner - only authorized users are allowed to run jobs using
      GSI-based transport level mechanisms. However, since they are not
      allowed to run *any* arbitrary command, they don't interfere with one
      another. Furthermore, it is easier to keep track of user requests
      this way because every single user can be accounted for (unlike the
      former where only the users are only accounted for as a single
      group).</li>
      <li> Users don't have to do their own data management. Using the
      traditional method, every user would have to stage input and output
      files manually. Furthermore, they would have to create new working
      directories for every single run (so that output files from older
      runs are not overwritten). On the other hand, Opal performs the data
      management for the user. It creates new working directories
      automatically for every run, and returns URLs to the user to retrieve
      the outputs when the execution is complete.</li>
      <li>Users don't have to be concerned with the schedulers being used at
      the back-end. The service is configured to use a scheduler supported
      by Globus (e.g. Condor, SGE) - the users are oblivious to this. Services
      also be configured to use other back-ends such as DRMAA. In
      the traditional approach, users would have to submit to a particular
      scheduler, and be mindful of what back-end is being used.</li>
      <li>Since the applications are exposed via a SOAP API, clients can be
      easily written in a variety of languages, and accessed from different
      platforms. Clients are shielded from any changes that happen at the
      backend (upgrades, etc) as long as the SOAP APIs and the URLs for
      connecting to the services stay the same. Currently, we have Java
      clients used in Gridsphere-based portals, Javascript clients used in
      the Mozilla-based Gemstone framework, and Python clients used in the
      PMV toolkit. Furthermore, workflow toolkits like Kepler can be used
      to orchestrate complex scientific pipelines based on Opal Web
      services.</li>
      </ul>
      </p>

    </section>
  </body>
</document>
