<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Publications and Presentations</title>
  </properties> 
  <body>
    <section name="Publications">
      <p> Publications &amp; Reports: </p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Design and Evaluation of Opal2: A Toolkit for Scientiﬁc Software as a Service.</b> Sriram Krishnan, Luca Clementi, Jingyuan Ren, Philip Papadopoulos and Wilfred Li. Submitted to ICWS 2009, IEEE International Conference on Web Services, 2009. (<a href="publications/opal2_icws.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
        <li><b>Providing Dynamic Virtualized Access to Grid Resources via the Web 2.0 Paradigm</b> Luca Clementi, Zhaohui Ding, Sriram Krishnan, Xiaohui Wei, Peter W. Arzberger, and Wilfred Li. GCE07, Grid Computing Environments Workshop (Supercomputing 2007), November 2007. <a href="http://www.collab-ogce.org/gce07/index.php/Main_Page">Conference Website</a></li>
        <li><b>Opal: Simple Web Services Wrappers for Scientific Applications.</b> Sriram Krishnan, Brent Stearn, Karan Bhatia, Kim K. Baldridge, Wilfred Li, and Peter Arzberger. In proceedings of ICWS 2006, IEEE International Conference on Web Services, September 2006 (<a href="publications/SDSC-TR-2006-5-opal.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
        <li><b>An End-to-end Web Services-based Infrastructure for Biomedical Applications.</b> Sriram Krishnan, Kim Baldridge, Jerry Greenberg, Brent Stearn, and Karan Bhatia. In proceedings of Grid 2005, 6th IEEE/ACM International Workshop on Grid Computing, November 2005 (<a href="publications/grid2005.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
        <li><b>Web Services-based Data Integration for Life Science Computations.</b> Sriram Krishnan, Brent Stearn, Karan Bhatia, Jerry Greenberg, Wilfred Li, Peter Arzberger, and Kim Baldridge. SDSC Technical Report TR-2005-2, 2005 (<a href="publications/SDSC-TR-2005-2-nbcr-soa.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section name="Presentations">
      <p>Presentations:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Providing Dynamic Virtualized Access to Grid Resources via the Web 2.0 Paradigm</b> Luca Clementi, et al. GCE07, Grid Computing Environments Workshop (Supercomputing 2007), November 2007 (<a href="talks/OpalGUI-GCE.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
        <li><b>Opal: Wrapping Scientific Applications as Web Services</b> Sriram Krishnan, et al. NBCR Special Seminar, SDSC, February 2006 (<a href="talks/opal-sdsc.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
        <li><b>An End-to-End Web Services-based Infrastructure for Biomedical Applications</b> Sriram Krishnan, et al. Grid2005, 6th IEEE/ACM International Workshop on Grid Computing, November 2005 (<a href="talks/nbcrsoa-grid2005.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
        <li><b>GSI-based Security for Web Services.</b> Sriram Krishnan. GEON Meeting, June 2005 (<a href="talks/geon-gsi.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
        <li><b>A Web Service Based Architecture for Biomedical Applications.</b> Sriram Krishnan, et al. International Symposium on Web Services for Computational Biology and Bioinformatics, Blacksburg, VA. May 2005 (<a href="talks/nbcr-krishnan.pdf">pdf</a>)</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>	  	 
