<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
<!--  <properties>
    <title>Welcome to Apache Logging Services</title>
    <author email="carnold@apache.org">Curt Arnold</author>
  </properties>  -->
  <body>
    <section name="About Opal Toolkit">
      <p>
      Automatic Web service wrappers for scientific applications on Grid resources.
      </p>
      <p>
 The Grid-based infrastructure enables large-scale scientific applications
 to be run on distributed resources and coupled in innovative ways. However,
 in practice, Grid resources are not very easy to use for the end-users who
 have to learn how to generate security credentials, stage inputs and
 outputs, access Grid-based schedulers, and install complex client software.
 There is an imminent need to provide transparent access to these resources
 so that the end-users are shielded from the complicated details, and free
 to concentrate on their domain science. Scientific applications wrapped as
 Web services alleviate some of these problems by hiding the complexities of
 the back-end security and computational infrastructure, only exposing a
 simple SOAP API that can be accessed programmatically by
 application-specific user interfaces. However, writing the application
 services that access Grid resources can be quite complicated, especially if
 it has to be replicated for every application. Towards that end, we have
 implemented Opal, which is a toolkit for wrapping scientific applications
 as Web services in a matter of hours, providing features such as
 scheduling, standards-based Grid security and data management in an
 easy-to-use and configurable manner.
      </p>
      <!-- 
    <p>The products of the Apache Logging Services Project included three logging frameworks: <a href="/log4j">log4j</a>
    for Java, <a href="/log4cxx">log4cxx</a> for C++ and <a href="/log4net">log4net</a> for the Microsoft .NET framework
    and a log viewer and analysis tool: <a href="/chainsaw">Chainsaw</a>.</p> -->
    </section>
    <section name="News">

        <iframe src="http://sourceforge.net/export/projnews.php?group_id=211778&amp;limit=20&amp;flat=1&amp;show_summaries=1"
                 width="100%" frameborder="0" height="400" />
<!--          style="margin-left: -10px; padding: 0" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"
          width="244" height="136"></iframe>-->
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
